<resources>
    <string name="app_name">BUI Handbook</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="nav_header_title">Android Studio</string>
    <string name="nav_header_subtitle">android.studio@android.com</string>
    <string name="nav_header_desc">Navigation header</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="menu_home">Home</string>
    <string name="menu_gallery">Gallery</string>
    <string name="menu_slideshow">Slideshow</string>
    <string name="menu_tools">Tools</string>
    <string name="menu_share">Share</string>
    <string name="menu_send">Send</string>

    <string-array name="chapters">
        <item>Preamble</item>
        <item>Resumption/Orientation</item>
        <item>Registration</item>
        <item>Matriculation</item>
        <item>Identity Cards</item>
        <item>Payments of Fees</item>
        <item>Hall of Residence</item>
        <item>Catering Services</item>
        <item>University Health Services</item>
        <item>The University Library</item>
        <item>Counselling Services in the University</item>
        <item>Code of Conduct</item>
        <item>Sexual Harassment</item>
        <item>Spiritual Life On Campus</item>
        <item>Dress Code</item>
        <item>Rules and Regulations Governing The Conduct Of Examination</item>
        <item>Student Discipline</item>
        <item>Social Life On Campus</item>
        <item>Drug Abuse</item>
        <item>Uses Of Social Media</item>
        <item>Student Representative Council</item>
        <item>Conclusion</item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="History">The major foundation of what has become Bowen University today was laid in 1854, That year, the family of the late Rev.
        Thomas Jefferson BOWEN started a school in ijaiye Orile in the present Oyo state of Nigeria. The school, comprising five stewards of the late Bowens,
        five other labourers, and a few others drawn to the fledgling school by sheer curiosity, has grown from this little beginning 1854 into thousands of
        Baptist Primary and Secondary School scattered across the country today.
        By 1960, there was a Baptist school almost everywhere that was found a Baptist congregation.\n    The idea of establishing a Baptist University in Nigeria
        was first conceived in 1938. This was borne out of the Baptist commitment to assist the people to develop their potentials to the fullest. The first bold step
        towards actualizing this vision was not taken until 1956 when a proposal was presented to the meeting of the Baptist Mission held in Eku from 11th to 14th December, 1956.
        On the 16th and 17th July, 1957, the joint meeting of the Executive Committees of the Baptist Mission of Nigeria and the Nigerian Baptist Convention endorsed the idea. Since then,
        the Nigerian Baptist Convention has worked tirelessly, committing time, material and human resources to actualizing the vision. Today, all these efforts are crystallized into the establishment
        of Bowen University, a significant landmark in the academic heritage of the Nigerian Baptist Convention,  making it the first Baptist Universitu in Africa.\n   On the 17th of July 2001, the Federal
        GOvernment of Nigeria approved the establishment of Bowen University and was subsequently licenced to operate by National UNiversities Commission.\n    On the 4th of November, 2002, Bowen University
        commenced academic activities, with 506 pioneering students admitted to its then three facilities: Agriculture, Science and Science Education, and Social and Management Science\n   College of Health Science
        of the University was established 2008 with programmes in physiology, Anatomy and Medicine. The Medical and Dental Council of Nigeria (MDCN) in 2016 granted full accreditation to the University in order to be
        able to induct its first set of Medical students.\n    The University presently has a College of Health Sciences made up of three facultie, while there are other five faculties in the University, with about 4,600 students.
        The university also has a postgraduate school running some programes.\n      The current Chairman of the University Governing Council and Pro\-Chancellor is Deacon Oluwole Abegunde while Deacon Prof.Bisi Adebowale and Late Dn.(Dr)
        Gamaliel Onosode, OFR, had earlier served as chairmen of the Governing Council.</string>

    <string name="coremotto">Excellence &amp; Godliness</string>
    <string name="values">The core values of the University shall be Excellence, Godliness, Entrepreneurship, Innovation, and Social Responsibility.</string>
      <string name="visionstatemen">A foremost Christian Institution of Excellence, Building God\-Fearing Leaders, Defining the Future.</string>
     <string name="missionstatement">Creating a conducive and dynamic teaching, learning and research environment that equips our graduates with christ\-like character, positive attitude and sterling leadership qualities.</string>
    <string name="philosophhy">The University is conceived as a centre of learning and research of distinction, combining academic excellence with love of humanity, borne out of a God\-fearing attitude, in accordance with the Baptist tradition of ethical behaviour, social responsibility and democratic ethos.</string>
    <string name="motto">The motto of the University is “Excellence and Godliness. ” This underpins all academic pursuit and social life on campus.</string>
    <string name="goalsandobjective">*To offer one of the best undergraduate trainings and one of the topmost postgraduate Studies in Nigeria.\n  *To integrate Computer training as well as simulation into every student\'s learning experience.\n  *To emphasize Scientific Research in Natural Science and Agriculture with focus on Biological Sciences, Chemical Sciences, Physics and Solar Energy, Food Production and Plant Protection.\n  *To develop graduates that seek to employ rather than be employed.\n  *To develop students with practical, communication and technological skills necessary for self and paid employment.</string>
    <!-- preamble -->
    <string name="introduction_pre">The Nigerian Baptist Convention in 2001 established BOWEN UNIVERSITY, Iwo (hereafter referred to as the University “).\n\ni. to provide courses of instruction and other facilities for the pursuit of learning in all its branches and to make those facilities available on proper terms to such persons as are equipped to benefit from them;\n\nii. to encourage and promote scholarship and conduct research in all fields of learning and human endeavor;\n\niii. to relate its activities to the social, cultural and economic needs of the people of Nigeria;\n\niv. to undertake any other service appropriate for a university of the highest standard;\n\nv. to promote and encourage academic research which will focus on those areas that will promote the development of the society at large. In pursuit of this goal, the various Departments and Institutes will be encouraged to conduct research into some of the urgent problems of contemporary society such as ecology, erosion control. Environmental degradation, drug abuse, cultism, etc. These shall be both at the Departmental level as well as through the various institutes.</string>
    <string name="historicalbackground_pre">i.Bist Mission came to Nigeria in 1850 with the determination not only to evangelize also introduce formal education to the people as a means to promote social development. Thus, by August 1854, the first Baptist missionary to Western Nigeria, the late Revd. Thomas Jefferson Bowen and his wife started a \'school\' comprising a handful of the stewards and labourers of the Bowens, and others from the community drawn by sheer curiosity. This has grown today into thousands of primary and secondary schools scattered across the country. Between 1915 and 1960, Baptist primary schools sprang up almost every where there was a Baptist congregation, while Baptist secondary schools also followed.\n\nii. As early as 1938, the Foreign Missions Board of the Southern Baptist Convention, USA had nursed the vision of establishing a Baptist University in Nigeria as a means of developing the potentials of the youths to the fullest. However, this initial idea was not formalized until it was presented to the meeting of the Baptist Mission held in Eku from the 11th to 14th December, 1956. Thus began a series of activities by a Survey Committee, which later transformed into the Baptist University Committee in 1957.\n\niii. The Baptist University project was first scheduled to start in 1961 and later rescheduled for 1964. The initial difficulty of raising sufficient funds locally delayed the take\-off until 1978 when the project was laid to rest. This became further complicated, when Chief A. Y. Eke, the then Minister of Education, called attention to the fact that there was no provision in Nigerian Constitution for a private university. Happily, with Government Policy initiative and consequent upon the promulgation of Decree No. 1 of 1993 legalizing the establishment of private universities, the Baptist University project was recieved and became actualized in 2001.\n</string>
    <string name="naming">The Nigerian Baptist Convention named the University \"Bowen University\" (of the Nigerian Baptist Convention ), Iwo, Osun State, Nigeria, after the Reverend Thomas Jefferson Bowen, who pioneered Baptist Mission work in  Nigeria in 1850.</string>
    <string name="philosophy">The University is conceived as a center of learning and research of distinction; combining academic excellence with love of humanity, borne out of God\-fearing attitude, in accordance with the Baptist tradition of ethical behaviour, social responsibility and democratic ethos.</string>
    <string name="themotto">The motto of the University is \"Excellence and Godliness \". This emphasizes the importance the University attaches to the attainment of excellence imbued with godliness in all its programmes and training. \"Excellence and Godliness\" is the principle underpinning all academic pursuits in the University.</string>
    <string name="logo">The focal point of the logo is the open book. The sun stands for light, life and energy . The palm frond symbolizes freshness and a new begining. It is the dominant foilage of the Nigerian rainforest belt, used for celebrations in the Christian tradition. The wheel embodies the unending and unbroken circle of knowledge informed by Godliness, and the Baptist mission steering humanity along the path of knowledge.</string>
    <string name="vision">A Foremost Christian Institution OF Excellence, Building  God\-Fearing Leaders, Defining the Future/.</string>
    <string name="mission">The Mission Statement of the University is as follows:\nCreating a conducive and dynamic teaching, learning and research environment that equips our graduates with Christ\-like character, positive attitude and sterling leadership qualities.</string>
    <string name="thevalues">The core values of the University shall be Excellence, Godliness, Entrepreneurship, Innovation, and Social Responsibility.</string>
    <string name="prospect">Bowen University currently runs nine Faculties with three in the College of Health Sciences,namely:\n\ni.   Agriculture \nii.  Basic Clinical Sciences\niii. College of Health Science\niv. Clinical Sciences \nv.  Education\nvi. Humanities\nvii. Law\nviii. Sciences\nix. Social and Mangement Sciences \n     There is a long term plan to establish other Faculties including:  Engineering, Environmental Sciences and Pharmaceutical Sciences.</string>
    <string name="management">i. The Student Affairs Unit caters for the general welfare of students. It is overseen by the Dean of Student Affairs who is directly responsible to the Vice\-Chancellor. Students are therefore encouraged to relate closely with the Unit.\n\nii. The Chaplaincy under the direction of the University Chaplain has been established to cater for the spiritual life on campus. Students are encouraged to take advantage of this Unit for counselling and advice.</string>
    <string name="anthem">i. Great Alma Mater,\n   Bowen University \n  Excellence and Godliness\n  Is our esteemed watchword\n  Though tongues may differ\n  In brotherhood we stand in Christ\n  Hail, Alma Mater Dear\n\nii. Great Alma Mater\n    Bowen University \n   On Christ foundation built\n   That can not be shaken \n   Other may falter\n   Our conviction we hold so firm\n   Hail, Alma Mater Dear</string>
    <!-- resumption/orientation -->
    <string name="orientation_resume">i. The orientation programme at the beginning of a new session is intended:\n      * To enable new student to settle down and adjust to the University culture, and also \n      * To afford students the opportunity to familiarize themselves with existing rules, regulations and procedure of the University.\n\nii. The Student Affairs Unit in\-co\-operation with other Departments and the Chaplaincy organizes the orientation programme.\n\niii. It is mandatory that ALL freshmen/women attend ALL the orientation activities and sign attendance register.\n\niv. Any student who has received a letter of admission before the orientation week, but fails to attend any of the orientation activities may have his/her admission withdrawn.</string>
    <string name="livingtogether">Coming into the University affords you the opportunity of meeting people of different character, ethnic group, skin complexion, etc. Understanding our personalities, as well as how others are different, will equip us to better manage our own lives and work more effectively with others.\nMore important, we are all born with certain differences in personality. The term personality is usually used to refer to the combination of a person\'s temperament (mood related expressions), and his or her consistent attitudes, interest, roles and behavior. The key aspects of personalities are temperament, habits, goals and self\-perception. Your personality is the totality of how you think, your \'default\' mood, attitudes and your behaviour especially as you interact with issues, people and your environment.\nBecause our personality are different, there are things we are prepared and motivated to do better than others. In like manner, there are things they can do better than us. We need to network and interact. Our personality should be used to complement others. We need others to fulfill our purpose and plans.\nIn Bowen University, like every other tertiary institution, you are allocated a room with roommates  most you have never met before. Your roommates are your immediate family and like the Bible tells us \'love your neighbor as you love yourself\'.\n    The following principles will help you relate well with your roommates.\n\ni. Introduction\nA brief introduction goes a long way in knowing your roommates. Introduce yourself by telling your roommates yourself , course of study, state of origin, where you reside etc. This helps foster a good relationship with them\n\nii Learn to communicate with your roommates\nIn communicating with your roommate, you not only become friends, you also know what your roommates likes/dislikes.\n\niii. Avoid making assumptions\nSince it virtually impossible to know exactly what your roommate is thinking about, learn to understand their behavior as well as ask questions for clarification.\n\niv. Treat your roommates the way you want to be treated \nThis is a golden rule. When dealing with your roommates especially when things are difficult, try to treat them the way you would want them to treat you if you were in their shoes.\n\nv. Don\'t be part of the problem\nDon\'t support your roommates when they are ding things which contradicts God\'s rules as well as the school\'s rules and regulation. Always learn to speak out and seek help from the counselors in the school.\nFinally, your roommates are now your immediate family, always learn to live as one, with the love of God binding you. Seek the best for your  roommates, pray for them, encourage them and love them.\n\nvi. However, if there are serious conflicts in your room, between you and others or among other roommates, please report the matter to the Hall Warden or the Counselors or the Dean, Student Affairs, who will take immediate steps to restoring relationships. If that fails, the Hall Warden may reallocate some or all the roommates to other rooms.</string>
    <!-- registration of students -->
    <string name="registration">The step\-by\-step registration process is as follows:\n\ni. clearance by the Admission Officer and collection of registration forms from the Academic Office.\n\nii. payment of prescribed fees and collection of payment clearance from the Bursar of hid designated staff.\n\niii. allocation of students into halls of residence only for the students who have paid their fees.\niv. clearance by the Faculty Office.\n\nv. completion of registration forms by consultation with the Heads of Department concerned.\n\nvi. submission of completed registration forms duly signed, to the Academic Office through the Faculty Office.\n\nvii. during the period of registration, all fresh students must register at the University Hospital.\n\nviii. a copy of the final completed registration from must be collected from the Faculty Officer to be kept by the student.</string>
    <!-- matriculation -->
    <string name="matric">All fresh students, properly registered as indicated above, shall be formally admitted into the University at a Matriculation Ceremony to be conducted on a date specified by Senate.\n\n(a) It is compulsory for all fresh students to take the Matriculation Oath to be administered by the Registrar on the Matriculation Day.\n\n(b) A student becomes a bona fide student of the University only after taking the Matriculation Oath, signing the Matriculation Register and being allotted a Matriculation number.\n\n(c) For emphasis, no registration is allowed for any student after the Matriculation Day.\nThe matriculation oaths reads as follows:\n\n“On admission, to studentship of Bowen University, Iwo,\nI……………………………………………………………………………………….\nSolemnly and sincerely pledge and declare that I will pay due respect and obedience to Bowen University, the Vice\-Chancellor and all other Officers of the University and that I will faithfully observe all regulations which may, from time to time be issued by them for the good order and governance of the university, including an order that I and/or the student body should make restitution for damage done by me and/or students to public property. In addition, I faithfully promise to refrain from any act of cultism, drug abuse, violence and other related or associated actions that may disrupt the smooth running of the University and/or bring the University into disrepute. So help me God.”\n\nNAME OF STUDENT (IN FULL):\n\-\-\-\-\-\-\-\-\-\-\-\-\-\-\-\-\-\-\--------------------------------------------------------------------\nMATRIC NO:----------------------------------------------------------------------\nFACULTY:--------------------------------------------------------------------------\nDEPARTMENT:-------------------------------------------------------------------\nSIGNATURE:----------------------------------------------------------------------\nDATE:------------------------------------------------------------------------------\n*For all official purposes in the University, students are expected \nto write their surnames first and in Capital Letters, followed by a \ncomma. Their two other names should be begin with Capital Letters.\n</string>
    <!-- identity cards -->
    <string name="identity">(a) Each student, upon registration in the University, is issued an official student identity car, valid for one session or as may be determined by the University.\n\n(b) Students may be required at any time to immediately identify themselves upon request by authorized University officials acting in the performance of their duties.\n\n(c) Some University facilities are open only to students who are able to show valid identity cards. Therefore, students are required to always have their identity cards on them and be ready to produce same on demand. For instance, no student will be admitted to the library, examinations, etc. without a valid identity card.\n\n(d) Note that the Identity Card is a property of Bowen University and must be submitted at the Student Affairs Unit if for any reason a student is to leave the University before graduation.\n</string>
    <!-- payments of fees -->
    <string name="payment">i. Bowen University is a private, fee-paying institution and all students are expected to pay prescribed fees for all services provided by the University, such services include:\n\n   * Academic activities\n   * Accommodation and convenience\n   * Other fees\n   * Health Care\n   * Bench fees\nFees may be changed from time to time as the need arises.\n\nii. To be considered a bona fide student of the University, a student is required to provide evidence of payment.\n\niii. Payment on semester basis of prescribed fees Is allowed for the convenience of parents/sponsors.\n\niv. All payments must be made by bank drafts from designated banks and/or any other electronic payment system with the banks.\n\nv. Students are issued receipts for all payments.\n\nvi. Clearance cards are issued to students on full payment of stipulated fees for each of the semester.\n\nvii. Students should ensure safety of their receipts and clearance cards; and such should be made available on request.\n\nviii. Each student is allotted a ledger account which contains student’s financial transaction for the duration of his/her course of study.\n\nix. Requests for refund of excess payment by students will only be entertained at the end of the course of study.\n\nx. Late registration attracts penalties and the actual amount is determined from time to time.\n\nA student who suspends his/her studies but does not obtain due approval and only notify the Bursary within the stipulated time will not be entitled to refund or waiver of payment fees.</string>
    <!-- catering services -->
    <string name="catering">(a)    The student catering services system is pay-as-you-eat in the cafeteria provided.\n\n(b)    It is expected that adequate provision shall be made by parents/guardians for their wards’ feeding before leaving home.\n\n(c)    Students are expected to observe the following rules in the Dining Halls:\n\ni. All students are required to conduct themselves very responsibly and are expected to eat within their means.\n\nii. Students should not beg Kitchen Staff for free food.\n\niii. All students are required to comply strictly with the regulations guiding the cafeteria/canteens as may be formulated by the University authority from time to time.\n\niv. Food is served on a first-come-first-served basis and no one should jump queues.\n\nv. Taking of food into the students’ hostels is normally prohibited.\n\nvi. Food for a sick person may be taken into the hostel only with written permission of the Domestic Hall Warden or Matron.\n\nvii. The kitchen is for employees only and is out of bounds to student. Any student who enters the kitchen area without the permission of the Kitchen Staff contravenes the University regulation.\n\nviii. Students are required to dress in modest and descent attire to the cafeteria. Slippers cannot be worn to the cafeteria.\n\nix. Dishes, cutlery and cooking utensils should not be removed from the cafeteria. Students found with cafeteria materials shall be liable to surcharge and disciplinary action.\n\nx. Students should exhibit good table manners whenever in the cafeteria. Any student who exhibits an anti-social behavior in and around the cafeteria, canteens and bukaterias will be made to face disciplinary action.\n\nxi. Students should strictly abide by the regulated times of opening and closing of the cafeteria and of serving meals. \n</string>
    <!-- university health services -->
    <string name="health">i. Every student must register with the University Hospital as part of the registration exercise.\n\nii. For any form of ailment/sickness, students should report promptly at the University Hospital for treatment, advice or any form of intervention.\n\niii. For official purposes only, the report of the Director of the University Health Services or Doctors designated by the Director is acceptable to the University.\n\niv. For treatments received outside the University, the medical report, if required for official purpose, must be endorsed by the Director of the University Health Services.\n\nv. There should be strict observance of visiting hours of 4.00 pm- 6.00 pm daily. Infringement will attract penalty or sanction.\n\nvi. Medical Registration and Screening on resumption is compulsory for every student.\n\nvii. Normally, and if necessary, not more than one person should accompany the sick to the sick.\n\nviii. A student who is ill or has any health challenge should report promptly and seek attention in the hospital. If in the hall of residence, must report to the hall officer or any staff member to facilitate medical help immediately.\n\nix.On no account should students take away any hospital document, INCLUDING CASE FILES, out of the hospital.\n\nx. Students should accord due respect to the hospital staff.\n\nxi. Health fees do not cover pregnancy test, abortion, delivery, drug rehabilitation, dentures, insurance of glasses and contact lenses, prosthesis or walking stick.\n\nxii.Hospital registration numbers MUST be presented on request at the hospital to access services, except in emergency.\n\nxiii. Routine medical services could be accessed free of charge in Bowen University Teaching Hospital (BUTH) by students studying there.\n\nxiv. The only institutions accepted for routine dope test and drug rehabilitation programme are the Bowen University Hospital, Bowen University Teaching Hospital or any other medical facility that the University may so approve from time to time.\n\nxv. As a Federal Government policy, all students in tertiary institutions in Nigeria must key to the Tertiary Institution Social Health Insurance Programme (TISHIP) of the National Health Insurance Scheme (NHIS). This applies to all bonafide students of Bowen University.\n\nxv. Clearance at the Hospital after completion studies is compulsory for every student.</string>
    <!-- the university library -->
    <string name="library">The Bowen University Library System comprising the Timothy Olagbemiro Library, the Law Library and the Medical Library aims at serving the needs of research, learning and teaching. The Library is a place for study, providing book and non-book materials, which supplement lectures and the quietness which serious students need. It is a service common to all and is generous in its opening hours (Monday-Friday: 8.00 am – 9.00pm; Saturday: 10.00 am-6.00 pm; Sunday: 4:30 pm – 6:30 pm and during the session and Extended Remedial Programme, Monday-Friday: 8.00 am-4.00 pm during holiday). \nBowen University Library System stocks books, journals, electronic resources and a number of disciplined-based multimedia items, access to which is guided by rules and regulations. It is essential that students comply with the Library rules to ensure maximum satisfaction of the services provided by the Library.\nAs part of the registration exercise, every student must register in the University Library. For new students who wish to borrow library books, they may register with the library using the library online registration platform. Thereafter, students should visit the Library regularly and conform to the rules of the library. Some of these rules are:\n\ni. All library users must show their Identity Cards before entry is granted into library. For new students, a photocopy of their admission letter affixed with a recent passport sized photo must be presented to the library.\n\nii. While entering the Library, bag(s) are to be dropped in the designated Cloak Room for Male and Female users. Ensure that valuables are removed from the bag. The Library will not be responsible for any lost item in your bag. The Library will not be responsible for any lost item in your bag.\n\niii. No food item or drink is allowed in the library.\n\niv. Library materials are to be treated with proper care when borrowed or when in use within the library.\n\nv. All library books or materials borrowed should be returned on or before the due date or renewed as authorized to avoid paying fines. Late return of books or materials, after due date, attracts a fine as applicable from time to time.\n\nvi. No library book or material should be taken out of the library without proper documentation.\n\nvii. Library users are expected to show respect for the rights of others by being quiet while studying or doing research. Therefore, all handsets are required to be put off or kept on silent mode while in the library. No call should be received in the library.\n\nviii. All library users must submit themselves for security check by the porters before leaving the library.\n\nix. Any act of misconduct or disobedience by a library user will attract appropriate sanctions.\n\nx. Students must comply with the University dress code while in the Library.\n\nFor detailed information, please read the Library Guide. </string>
    <!-- conclusion -->
    <string name="conclusion">The rules and regulations in this handbook are subjected to review from time to time by the Senate.\n\“This Information Handbook supersedes earlier editions.\"</string>
    <!-- halls of residence -->
    <string name="accomodation_halls">i. By policy, the University provides accommodation for all registered students and it is therefore compulsory for all undergraduate students to live on campus.\n\nii. On arrival, students will be allocated rooms in halls of residence as determined by Student Affairs Unit.\n</string>
    <string name="beddings">Students are required to come with their own beddings (i.e. bed sheet, pillow cases and blankets). Students will be responsible for the cleaning of their rooms and for their laundry.</string>
    <string name="conductinthehall">i. Students cannot sell, buy, advertise, solicit, offer or market items in the halls of residence and the University environment except officially authorized. Where this rule is violated, those found culpable will face disciplinary action.\n\nii. Screening of beds in the halls of residence is not allowed except for the use of transparent mosquito net.</string>
    <string name="exeats">i. In order to be away from the University campus either by going into town or travelling out of town, an undergraduate student must obtain an exeat issued by the Student Affairs Unit.\n\nii. For the purpose of travelling out of town, the Dean of student Affairs must approve such an exeat, which should have been applied for, at least 48 hours before such a trip. Undergraduate students are not normally allowed to travel more than once in a month.\n\niii. Exeats will not normally be issued to cover a period of worship and group devotions.\n\niv. Any student found to be away from the University without an exeat will face disciplinary action.</string>
    <string name="visitinghours">i.Students may be allowed to visit their fellow students in other halls of residence, but not during the period of general assembly or worship service and not beyond 9.00 pm on any day.\n\nii. Visitation to halls of residence of the opposite sex is not permitted.</string>
    <string name="offcampus">All proposed off campus activities by students of the University are to be submitted in writing for consideration and recommendation through the Student Affairs Office for the Vice-Chancellor\’s approval. The request should among other things include:\n\ni. The destination, purpose of the trip, time of leaving the campus and time of returning.\n\nii. The name(s) of the Chaperone(s) of staff of the University. Chaperone(s) are to take proper briefing from the Vice-Chancellor prior to the commencement of the journey.\n\niii. The method of transportation (vehicle, the owner and arrangement in place ).\n\niv. The endorsement of the staff adviser or the University official in charge.\n\nv. In the case of activities organized by student groups, parental consent must be sought by the student before he/she can be allowed to travel with the group.\n\nvi. Applications for off-campus programme must be received for approval at least a week before the departure.\n\nvii. Organizers of off-campus activities must obtain the Vice-Chancellor’s approval in writing before embarking on such trips.\n\nviii. Students who are not accredited as members of the group should under no circumstance accompany the group.\n\nix. The group and vehicle(s) designated for the off-campus programme are to go to the exact destination alone and return to campus with all the contingents.</string>
    <string name="socilgathering">All proposals for any form of celebration and social gatherings to be held on campus by individuals, clubs and associations are to be submitted in writing for consideration and recommendation through the Staff Adviser or the Hall warden concerned, for the approval of the Dean of Student Affairs. Organizers of programme without due approval will be appropriately sanctioned.\n</string>
    <string name="halsforsocilgathering">i. Permission to use halls of residence for social activities must be by the written permission of the Deann of Student Affairs with at least 48 hours\’ notice.\n\nii. Individual students who wish to use the common room for social gathering should submit their request in writing through the Hall Warden or in the case of clubs and associations, through the Staff Adviser, for the approval of the Dean of Student Affairs.\n\niii. No social gathering of students will be allowed during any university official activities.\n\niv. Any form of anti\-social behavior (e.g. smoking, drinking of alcohol, use of hard drugs, fighting, etc.) during the gatherings is strictly prohibited. Any violation of these regulations will be referred to the Student Disciplinary Committee.\n\nv. All authorized activities should normally take place in the Common Room.\n\nvi. Parties must not last beyond 6:00 pm.\n\nvii. Music played in the rooms or at approved social gatherings should not disturb other residents. Every musical composition played through/on any electronic device must be in harmony with the expected high moral standards of the University.\n\nviii. Under no circumstance should any student produce noisy sound to the detriment of other students or hostel staff in the halls of residence.</string>
    <string name="electricalappliance">i. Only torches, cell phone lights and rechargeable lamps are allowed during power outages. Naked flames are prohibited.\n\nii. Under no circumstances must electrical appliances and extension cords or multiple outlets be brought into the halls of residence or used by students. Appliances such as immersion heaters, heating coils, electric cookers, toasters, grills, television sets, refrigerators and hot plates are prohibited.\n\niii. Only electric not more than 1500w is allowed but this should not be used in the students’ roo, except in the laundry room or kitchenette. However, such electric kettle must have the capacity to switch off automatically.</string>
    <string name="rawfood">i. Students are forbidden from keeping raw food items like indomie, spaghetti. Rice, yam, etc. in the hostel.\n\nii. Any student who violates (i) above shall face appropriate disciplinary action.</string>
    <string name="nightcontrol">i. All student should be in their halls of residence by 10.00 pm.\n\nii. The only lights permitted in the rooms apart from overhead lights are desk and rechargeable lamps, which are to be provided by students.\n\niii. Bed Checks shall be performed in the Halls of residence daily from 10.30 pm and any student absent shall receive appropriate sanctions(s)</string>
    <string name="inspection"> i. Students must make their beds and keep their rooms clean and tidy.\n\nii. There shall be monthly sanitation exercise and all students must participate in the exercise. Failure to do so without permission shall attract serious disciplinary action.\n\niii. Students are forbidden from:\n\n(a) Indiscriminately urinating and defecating outside the toilets and in unauthorized areas.\n\n(b) Bathing outside the prescribed bathrooms.\n\n(c) Disturbing others playing music.\n\niv. Violation of (i) and (iii) above shall attract appropriate disciplinary action.\n\nv. Appropriate University officials reserve the right to inspect the hostels and rooms at any time.</string>
    <string name="damage">i. Students must not tamper with, dismantle, attempt to dismantle or interfere with the normal functioning of equipment, facilities and security fixtures in the halls of residence and university environment.\n\nii. Nail tacks and anything else that can damage the walls must not be used on the walls.\n\niii. There should be no movement of furniture or property from one room to another and no alteration is permitted on the furniture, including fixtures, lights, woodwork or locks.\n\niv. All students in the room where damages are found will pay for damages at the end of the session.\n\nv. Should the damage occur in the laundry, common room, toilets or bathroom, all students on that floor will be held responsible.\n\nvi. There should be no pasting of advertisements of any kind on the wall.\n\nvii.Students advertisement, when authorized, should not be pasted on the notice boards in the hostel without the approval of the hall warden.\n\nviii. Under no circumstance should student place mattresses on the floor.</string>
    <string name="pets"> For health and sanitary reasons, pets are prohibited in and around the university halls of residence. Any breach of the rule will attract appropriate disciplinary action.\n</string>
    <string name="squatting">"i. Any student who stays or squats in a room not allocate to him/her will be made to face disciplinary action.\n\nii. A student who aids and abets squatting of another student at any time including at examination period and/or harboring strangers/visitors in rooms will also face disciplinary action.\n\niii. Any student who harbors a stranger and an unauthorized visitor in the hostel shall be made to face disciplinary action.</string>
    <string name="personalsecurity">i. The University does not accept responsibility for any loss of personal property in the halls of residence.\n\nii. Students are strongly advised to keep all valuables and large sum of money with commercial banks.\n\niii. Doors should always be locked and keys removed when leaving the room. The keys must be kept at the Hall Supervisor’s office.\n\niv. Students must not leave personal belongings in their halls of residence during long vacations.\n\nv. Any personal equipment (e.g. personal computers, handsets etc.) used on routine basis should be registered at the Student Affairs Office.\n\nvi. Students must not use/possess phones with more than the monetary value approved by the University from time to time.\n\nvii. Lending and borrowing of large sums of money among students is prohibited.</string>
    <!-- counselling -->
    <string name="introductin_counselling">Career guidance and counseling services are important factors in university education, particularly in the production of sound graduates.\nThe University has a Counselling Office within the Student Affairs Unit charged with the responsibility of providing professional assistance and guidance in preventing academic, personal and/or psychological problems.</string>
    <string name="counsellingservices">The Counselling Office is manned by professional counsellors, and it provides a number of services designed to give insight into students’ educational, vocational and socio-personal problems. The counseling services include: educational, vocational, appraisal, planning and placement, information, follow up, referral and socio-personal services.\n\ni. Educational/Academic Service \nThis service is rendered to students with respect to academic matters, which may include poor academic performance, school phobia, problem with choice of course, lack of motivation to learn , examination phobia and difficulties in adjusting to University environment.\nThis professional assistance helps to identify, clarify and resolve students’ problems and enables them perform optimally in their academic work.\n\nii. Vocational Service\nThe Counselling Office organizes career seminars for students; professionals from different fields are engaged for this purpose. Students are sensitized on the requirements, qualification, mode of entry and remuneration relating to their profession.\nThrough these services, students are able to acquire first-hand information about various occupations and even ask questions which will facilitate their decision-making.\n\niii. Behavioural Modification Programme\nThe behavioural modification programme aims at appraising students\’ behaviour, identifying tendencies towards anti-social behaviour and assisting in re-directing the focus of students.\nThis service is achieved through the collection and analysis of series of objective and subjective personal psychological and social data.\n\niv. Information Service\nThe Counselling Office provides educational information, such as award of scholarship and bursary, vocational and socio-personalinformation that are designed to help students adjust to the environment and help develop their full potentials.\n\nv. Follow-Up Service\nThis service is to check if the client/student in question is doing well and is progressing as planned. If not, these follow up sessions are used to work with the client some more if he/she is still having trouble functioning.\n\nvi. Referral Service\nIn certain circumstances, students may be referred by the counselling section to experts in specialized fields.\n\nvii. Socio- Personal Service\nThis service focuses on the students’ socio-personal problems relating to personality maladjustments, which may result into unhappiness, anger, frustration, truancy, failure, lack of motivation, confusion, inferiority complex, loneliness, aggressiveness and shyness. Psychological problems such as psychosis, neurosis and drug addiction are also addressed.</string>
    <!-- code of conduct -->
    <string name="introduction_conduct">i. The University\’s vision and mission is primarily for the intellectual, social and cultural development of its students. The University also aims at inculcating good character as an integral part of that education.\nA candidate\’s acceptance of admission offer to the University implies that the student has accepted to abide by the rules and regulations that may from time to time be made for its good governance.\n\nii. A letter of undertaking must be signed by the student and his/her parent/guardian during registration.\n\niii. Such undertaking carries with it an obligation that the University\’s best standards, rules and other conditions established by the constituted authorities of the University.\n\niv. Every student of the University is required to maintain a high standard of personal integrity. The University regards as a serious offence any act of unethical, immoral, dishonest, disloyal or destructive behaviour, as well as violation of University regulations. It is the responsibility of each student not only to acquaint himself/herself with these Rules and Regulations, but also to uphold them at all times, and with special regard to the University\’s motto of \“Excellence &amp; Godliness\”</string>
    <string name="guideline">i. Any student who displays any form of disrespect bordering on contempt, to any official of the University, while the latter is performing his/her official assignment will be subject to disciplinary action.\n\nii. Any student who writes an insulting letter to an official of the University will be subject to disciplinary action.</string>
    <string name="lineofcomm">i. For academic matter including complaints on registration and examination results, a student may communicate directly, verbally and in writing, with his/her Head of Department or Dean of Faculty.\n\nii. For non-academic matters such as welfare matters, mobilization for NYSC, etc., the approved line of communication is through the Dean of Student Affairs.</string>
    <string name="useofcellphones">The University allows Bowen Students to have personal cell phones, pagers, beepers, electronic reminder and smart wristwatches. The following rules and regulations are set in place for the use of these devices:\n\ni. The devices must be switched off during lectures, practical(s) and worship services; and in the Library.\n\nii. Students are not allowed to bring cell phones into the examination halls.\n\niii. The University does not allow the use of cellphones by students while In discussion with lectures or university administrative officials.\n\niv. Students are not normally expected to use their cell phones for commercial purposes. Students wishing to use cell phones for commercial purposes should apply to the Director of Bowen Commercial Services for approval through the Dean of Student Affairs.\n\nv. All electronic devices such a cell phones, pagers, beepers and reminders should be registered with Student Affairs Office.\n\nvi. Students are responsible for the safe-keeping of their electronic devices.\n\nvii. Students are advised to re-charge their electronic devices using only appropriate sockets.\n\nviii. The University will from-time-to-time regulate the type of cell phones that students of the University bring to the campus. For the 2017/2018 session, students cannot own any phone costing more than N25.000.00 when new.\n\nix. Students should not use their electronic devices to take indecent photographs or distribute such. In addition, students should not use their electronic devices to send messages or photographs that may intimidate, coerce and blackmail other students, University. Infringement of this rule will attract disciplinary measures.</string>
    <!-- sexual harassment -->
    <string name="introduction_sexualharassment">Bowen University, as faith-based University, is founded on godly doctrines, where morality complements academic performance in the award of degrees.\nIn line with its mission of running a unique institution with unquestionable Christian morality, Bowen University places zero tolerance on any act or acts of sexual harassment.\nSexual harassment is a morality problem that negatively affects its victims militating against the attainment of educational aims and objectives.</string>
    <string name="definition">Sexual harassment is any attempt made by an opposite/same sex to coerce an unwilling person into a sexual relationship or to subject such a person to unwanted sexual attack or to punish a refusal to succumb to any sexual overture.</string>
    <string name="formsofsexualharassment">Sexual harassment can manifest in various forms such as:\n\ni. Utterances of offensive or suggestive remarks with sexual undertone.\n\nii. Nonverbal communication with sexual undertone (i.e. Leering or ogling, etc.).\n\niii. Sexist remarks about a person\’s clothing, body or activities.\n\niv. Unnecessary deliberate physical contacts suggestive of sexual undertone i.e. touching, patting or rubbing, etc.\n\nv. Demanding sexual favour as gratification for a task or service rendered.\n\nvi. Demanding sexual favour from a person through the use of threat.\n\nvii. Using power and authority in a way to make a person submit to sexual favour.</string>
    <string name="modesofreporting">In case of sexual harassment, students are requested to contact any of the following University Officers:\ni.   Dean, Student Affairs\nii.  Deputy Deans, Student Affairs(Male and Female)\niii. University Counsellors\niv. Chaplains\nv.  Vice-Chancellor</string>
    <!-- spiritual life on campus -->
    <string name="introduction_spiritual">i. BOWEN UNIVERSITY is established among other things to attain “Excellence &amp; Godliness”. The Nigeria Baptist Convention, as the Proprietor of this institution. Sincerely believes that the future leaders of this country and the world at large must be tutored to accept the due processes of divine guidance as part of their educational pursuit.\n\nii. Students are therefore encouraged to share biblical beliefs, which the Baptist cherishes and practices.</string>
    <string name="chaplaincystatement">i. Exists to glorify God, attract lives, link them to make progress in faith and identify their worth in Ministry.\n\nii. It is mandatory for all students to register with the Chaplaincy at the point of entry.</string>
    <string name="devotions">Having a personal relationship with God is a vital part of the Christian life. It is hoped that students will take advantage of the serene and beautiful surroundings of the campus to have a daily \‘quite time\’ with God for about thirty minutes (5.00 a.m. \– 6 a.m.) daily, using for example \“Seek Daily\”, \“Spiritual Diet\”, \“The Word for Today\”, \“Everyday with Jesus\” for personal devotion in their individual rooms. This will be followed by group devotion (6.00a.m. \– 6.30a.m.) on hall or block basis as may be organized by the Hall Representatives or Devotional Leaders using “Seek Daily”. Students are to meet together daily for evening devotion (10.00p.m. \– 10.20.p.m.) on hall or block basis. Every student is to participate in this devotion.</string>
    <string name="worshipservice">All students are to attend all worship services and conduct themselves in harmony with the holiness of Christian worship. No other form of worship or worship services is permitted on Bowen University campuses.\n\n1. The following are the normal weekly worship periods:\n  (a) University General Worship Services\n   i. Sunday Morning Services;\n(Sunday School Time: 9.00a.m. \– 10.00a.m.)\n(Sunday Worship service 10.00a.m. -12.00noon)\n\n  ii. Time: (Wednesday: 10.30a.m. \– 11.20a.am. except on special occasions).\n\nNote: Attendance at the above worship services is compulsory. No other activities are permitted during the above periods of worship services. Furthermore, the library, Cafeteria, telephone room, and other utility points shall not operate during worship and corporate devotions.\n\nStudent Fellowship\n   i. Baptist Students Fellowship(BSF):\nThursday Evening: 7.00\-8.00 pm\n\nNote: Attendance is compulsory for all students.\n  ii. Baptist Student Fellowship: Sunday Evening:\n5.00pm-7.00pm. This is voluntary.\n\n iii. Voluntary Bible Study:\nMonday Evening: 6.00\-7.00pm\nNote: Unauthorized Students Fellowship in any form is not allowed.\n\n2. University Spiritual Annual Activities\n    i.  Bowen BSF Executive members retreat.\n    ii. General Chapel Workers Retreat.\n   iii. Leslie Tuller Memorial Lecture and Bursary Awards.\n   iv. Christmas Carol/Easter celebrations\n    v. Revival Services\nNote: For the last three spiritual activities (iii - v), attendance is compulsory for all students. Weekend exeats shall not be granted during such programmes.\n\nNote: No other activities shall be permitted during the above periods of worship services. Furthermore, the library, cafeteria, telephone room and other utility pints shall not operate during worship and corporate devotions.</string>
    <string name="codeofethics">The following are some of the activities for which emphasis are placed in keeping the Lord\’s Day holy:\n\n1) Attendance in Chapel Worship services and hostel devotions is mandatory.\n\n2) Students should participate fully in all worship services and spiritual devotions.\n\n3) Observing godly reverence at the Chapel, whether standing or sitting, praying or singing during worship services.\n\n4) Covering of head during worship services is required for all female students.\n\n5) Dressing decently should be strictly adhered to by all students.\n\n6) Mobile phones and all electronic ICT gadgets should be switched off during worship services.\n\n7) Orderliness in worship services is highly required.\n\n8) Eating, chewing and drinking during Chapel services are prohibited.\n\n9) Students are required to come to chapel with their ID cards.\n\n10) Lateness to Chapel will attract sanctions.\n\n11) Engaging in activities such as making Sunday a laundry day: participation in sports and games are not encouraged.\n\nNote: Students who fails to comply with the above-stipulated regulations will be appropriately sanctioned.</string>
    <string name="weekofspiritualactivities">i. Every semester, a week shall be devoted to special Christian activities as determined ny the authorities of the University.\n\nii. It is mandatory for all students to attend the programme Weekend exeats shall not be granted during that week.\n\niii. Students are encouraged to participate for their spiritual upliftment in the following voluntary programme:\n\na) Discipleship training \nb) Baptismal Classes, leading to baptism by immersion.\nc) Lord’s Supper \nd) Every 1st day of the month, early morning prayer meeting 6. 00a.m\-7.00a.m.\ne) Other spiritual programmes as organized by the Chaplaincy.</string>
    <string name="bbsf">i. It is required for all students of Bowen University to belong to the BBSF, there shall be no other religious organization on the campus;\n\nii. The BBSF officers and the student representative council members are Student Representatives in the University. BBSF officers Election shall take place in the second March semester of every academic session.\n\niii. The presentation of new BBSF officers shall be done within two weeks of successful conduct of election. An officer can serve in an office for one year and be re-selected only once after the first year of service;\n\niv. There shall be BBSF dues to be paid by every student and to be collected by the University.\n\nv. Students are not to take exact during the BBSF programmes and special events;\n\nvi. BBSF programmes are mandatory for all students;\n\nvii. All students are expected to come to worship services and BSF programmes with their copies of Bible.</string>
    <string name="studentworker">For student to participate in Chapel Ministries, it is mandatory for him/her to undergo some basic Discipleship programmes.</string>
    <!-- dress code -->
    <string name="introduction_dresscode">i. All students must dress formally excerpt when they are in their hostels or actively participating in sporting activities or farm practicals.\n\nii. While maintaining good taste with high morality and modesty, the appearance of every student should be characterized by neatness, purity and simplicity, which must conform with Christian standard and virtue.</string>
    <string name="femaledress">The following regulations apply to all times to all females dressing on campus.\ni. Female students dress for lecturers or general campus wear should consist of skirt suit, skirt and blouse or a gown with a pair of neat, covered shoes or sandals.\n\nii. Skirts or gowns should cover the knee and must not be slit above the knee.\n\niii. Transparent, sheer, or tight-fitting blouses, sweaters or skirts are to not permitted.\n\niv. Dresses with low necklines or dresses that do not fully cover the shoulder and armpits are not permitted.\n\nv. Shorts, slacks and similar attire should not be worn outside the residence halls on campus.\n\nvi. The use of T-Shirts and faze-caps in lecture and examination halls is not encouraged.\n\nVii. Wearing of Jeans by students in the University during official hour prohibited.\n\nviii. Piercing of any part of the body, other than the ear (for ear ring) is not encouraged.\n\nix. Tattooing on any part of the body is prohibited.\n\nx. Casual wears are allowed on Fridays; however, no Jeans or Slipper should be worn alongside.\n\nxi. Excessive facial make-up, coloured nail-polish, artificial nails and bleaching must be avoided.\n\nxii. Students are allowed, moderate use of unnatural braided hair or attachment, which in any case should not exceed neck\-length.\n\nxiii. Unnatural braided hair or attachment should match with the natural hair\-colour. Multi\-colour hair\-do is prohibited on Bowen University campus.\n\nxiv. The hair should  be well groomed (neat and tidy) all the time.\n\nxv. Use of jewelry should be moderate. Nose rings and ankle chains are prohibited.\n\nxvi. Noisy, bogus shoes and slippers should be avoided.</string>
    <string name="maledress">i. Men\’s dress for lectures or general campus wear should consist of trousers (not Jeans ), shirt and tir to fit. The trousers should, however cover the ankle.\n\nii. Short of any kind should not be worn outside the hostel.\n\nIii. Wearing of long\-sleeved shirts, without buttoning the sleeves and/or folding the sleeves is not allowed.\n\niv. The use of caps, wearing of T-shirts in lecture and examination halls is not encouraged.\n\nv. T-shirts, faze-cap and scarves are not allowed during official hours in the University i.e. 8.00 am-4.00 pm (Monday-Friday).\n\nvi. Casual wears are allowed on Fridays; however, no Jeans or slipper should be worn alongside.\n\nvii. Men Should not go bare\-footed or without shirts anywhere on campus except when playing outdoor games.\n\nviii. Men are not allowed to wear muscle tops, braided hair, earrings, necklace, bangles, hand and ankle chains, nose rings, beads, etc. in the University.\n\nix. Bushy/Unkept hair, beard, sideburn and moustache are not allowed. Students who refused to comply may face the Student Disciplinary Panel.</string>
    <string name="sundaydress">While attending Church worship, students are expected to be in respectable dresses either African or Foreign. Jeans and T\-Shirts are not allowed for Sunday worship. Proper shoes must be worn. Slippers are not allowed.</string>
    <!-- drug abuse -->
    <string name="introduction_drugabuse">Bowen University as a faith\-based University is founded on Godly doctrines, where morality complements academic performance in the award of degrees.\nDrug abuse is a problem that negatively affects its victims and has been implicated in a wide range of problems militating against the attainment of educational aims and objectives. Therefore, Bowen University places zero tolerance on any act of drug abuse.</string>
    <string name="definitions">The use of drugs that are not prescribed by a medical personnel after clinical assessment of the Health condition of a patient id Drug Abuse. However, a phenomenon whereby a person uses drugs (usually psychotropic drugs) that affect the mood and mental status of the user, sometimes giving a sense of euphoria and feeling high, is the social abuse known to most people.\nDrug Abuse, in this context, is the consumption of psychoactive , relaxing or performance enhancing drugs for non\-therapeutic or non\-medical effects.</string>
    <string name="formsofdrugabuse">The following Druga/substances are prohibited; therefore students must not possess, consume o distribute them within and outside the University Campus.\n  1. Alcohol\n  2. Morphine(MOP)\n  3. Marijuana/Weed(Igbo)\n  4. Methamphetamine(MET)\n  5. Opiates(OPI)\n  6. Benzodiazepines(BZO)\n  7. Barbiturates(BAR)\n  8. Amphetamines(AMP)\n  9. Phencyclidine(PCP)\n 10. Methadone(MTD)\n  11. Cigarette\n 12. Heroin\n 13. Cocaine\n 14. Any other drug not prescribed by a medical practitioner.\n 15. Items including rizzler, fire lighter, vapourizer, e\-cigarette, etc. are also prohibited.\n 16. Any natural product including plants, roots, bark of trees, etc.</string>
    <string name="addressinngdrugabuse">As part of its mission to the development of the society, Bowen University places utmost importance on preventing students from drug abuse and assisting those already involved in the act. In view of this, the following steps are employed to address the menace of drug abuse:\n\ni. Upon resumption, fresh students shall be subjected to dope test.\n\nii. All students and their language shall be subjected to a search by designated University officials before entering the halls of residence.\n\niii. Students who are already involved in drug abuse are encourage to seek assistance from the University Counsellors.\n\niv. Any student apprehended for possession, consumption or distribution of prohibited substances will be asked to leave the University campus and during this period and be required to undergo rehabilitation.\n\nv. Students are required to note that the University reserves the right to subject any student to a dope test at any time as part of its efforts to curb drug abuse.\n\nvi. Any student who refuses to present himself/herself timely upon invitation for a dope test shall be sanctioned.\n\nvii. A student shall bear the cost of the dope test if the result is found to be positive to prohibited substances. The cost shall be as determined by the University from time to time.\n\nviii. A student who is found to be positive to prohibited substances shall be required to undergo Drug Rehabilitation Therapy upon the student\’s voluntary submission and bearing all costs of the therapy at any health facility for such a period of time that the University may so prescribe.\n\nix. A student may be expelled from the University following the decision of the Student Disciplinary Committee if found to have abused any prohibited substance.</string>
    <string name="drugfreeclub">Drug Free Club (DFC) is a club established by the University in collaboration with the National Drug Law Enforcement Agency (NDLEA).\nAmongst other things, the club aims to:\n\ni.Educate students to abstain from drug abuse.\n\nii. Encourage students to abstain from drug abuse.\n\niii. Assist students who are already involved in drug abuse to come free of drugs.\nMembership shall be opened to students who desire to help promote a drug free society. The club shall operate under supervision of the Student Affairs Unit.</string>
    <!-- social life on campus -->
    <string name="introduction_social">Bowen University is a co-educational institution where wholesome association is encouraged and considered necessary for personal development. Friendly relationship between men and women in open-group activities is desirable.</string>
    <string name="male_female">i. Unrestricted association between men and women, including any conduct such as clandestine meeting and loitering in the dark and secluded places that might lay the morals of a student open to question is forbidden.\n\nii. Courtship amongst male and female adults is expected and respected. Courtship however, should not violate University regulations. Courtship between the same gender i.e. male/male or female/female is not permitted in the University.\n\niii. If a student decides to get married during his/her studentship, the University must be formally informed; such student must officially notify his/her Department, Faculty, the Dean of Student Affairs and the Registrar. Thereafter, the information on the changed marital status must be given in writing to the Registrar, the Dean of Student Affairs, the Dean of Faculty and Head of Department of the student concerned.\n\niv. A married female student who becomes pregnant must seek for leave of absence from her studies (suspension of studies) for a minimum of one semester to deliver the baby. No married female students will be allowed to nurse her baby in the student hostel. However, off-campus accommodation for such students can be permitted on application.\n\nv. An unmarried female student who is found to be pregnant without an evidence of marriage will be requested to leave the University. A report on such student must reach the Vice-Chancellor through the Hall Warden of the student concerned and through the Dean of Student Affairs after confirmation from the Director of University Health Services of the medical state of the Student. A minimum of two-semester rustication from the University is to be meted out to such students because getting pregnant without being married is against the values of Bowen University, which is a faith\-based University. Parents of such student would be invited and informed of the pregnancy while the affected female student should be counselled to take responsibility for, care for and carry the pregnancy to term. As a faith-based institution, the University is pro-life and speak against abortion. Therefore, pregnant female students shall be asked to stay away from the University as they may no longer be able to cope with the rigors of academics and more so as the University lacks facilities on campus to support a pregnant student. After delivery and wearing of the baby, the student shall apply, through the Dean, Student Affairs, to resume her studies.\n\nvi. A male student identified to have committed the offence in (iv) above will be sanctioned for a period not less than two semesters.</string>
    <string name="requirements">i. Student’s Clubs and organizations will only be registered and recognized after prospective clubs/Organizations must have satisfied the following conditions:\n\n  * Submission of prescribed Application Forms, duly completed.\n\n  * Submission of letters of undertaking from a staff adviser/patron.\n\n  * Submission of the club objectives and constitution, which must be in agreement with the objectives of the University. \n\nii. All Clubs must renew their registration yearly at the beginning pf each session; accompanied by audit report of the previous year.\n\niii. Student Club Registration should be processed for Senate approval by the First semester every session.  \n\niv. No organization shall be allowed to have special dress.\n\nv. Any publication of society that contains scurrilous and malicious attacks on individuals will be banned and the members disciplined.\n\nvi. All writers’ club and names of their magazines/journals must be registered in the Student Affairs Office before publication commences. The names of all writers or columnists must equally be registered. Approval for a change of name of any registered organization/club must be obtained from the Student Affairs Officer before commencement of operations under new name.\n\nvii. Any interference with the course of dispensation of discipline on students through frivolous writing or other actions liable to obstruct the University authorized official from performing his/her duty will result in the suspension of the guilty student or group of students responsible. This is in addition to other disciplinary measures that might be taken against such students(s).</string>
    <string name="guestsfromoutside">i. In keeping with the University’s traditional commitment to freedom of enquiry and the pursuit of truth, students’ organizations are allowed to organize activities featuring guest speakers of their choice from within and outside the University.\n\nii. However, the University has an obligation to ensure that activities on the campus are conducted in appropriate manner with requisite protocol. Where a Guest Speakers is to be invited outside of the University, the approval of the Vice\-Chancellor must be obtained in writing before contacting the person concerned.\n\niii. Before musicians or gospellers can be invited for any activity on campus, an application must be made in writing through the Dean of Student Affairs to the Vice\-Chancellor.\n\niv. The approval of the Vice\-Chancellor must be obtained in writing before contacting and bringing any musicians or gospellers to the campus for any event or social activity.</string>
    <string name="sports">i. Students are encouraged too make us of all sporting facilities provided by the University.\n\nii. Friendly matches are allowed between faculties, Departments and Hall of Residence.\n\niii. The approval of the Dean/Staff Adviser/Sport Coordinator must be obtained in writing  before any Departmental friendly games.\n\niv. Students are advised to appear at trainings, competitions and Wellness Centres in their Sport Kits \– T\-shirt/vest, Short/Track down, socks/Canvas/Sneakers.\n\nv. Leggings and Slippers are not allowed at each of the venues.\n\nvi. The University encourages healthy sporting competition with sister Universities.\n\nvii. Sporting Equipments/Materials collected for use must be returned immediately after the training/competition.\n\nviii. A twice weekly(Tuesday 5:00pm \– 6:30pm and Saturday 6:30am \– 9:00am) fitness programme is compulsory for all students.</string>
    <!-- rules and regulation -->
    <string name="eligbility">"i. All students who registered for courses in a given semester are eligible to sit for examination in those courses except students in the following categories:\n\n   (1). a student who is absent from the University for upwards of three weeks without official permission; such a student shall normally be deemed by Senate to have voluntarily withdrawn from the University.\n\n    (2). a student who fails to attend up to 80% of lectures or practicals in any course.\n\nii. The implementation of cases listed in 1.1 is subject to Senate approval on the recommendation of the Faculty board.</string>
    <string name="candidates">i. Every candidate shall:\n\n   (1).  be admitted into the examination hall only on the production of the University Identity Card and Examination Card.\n\n   (2).  ensure that he/she acquaints him/herself with and adhere strictly to the instructions governing examinations in the University, including those printed on the front cover of the examination answer booklet.\n\n   (3). have the full responsibility of ensuring, before the commencement of any examination or test, that nothing incriminating is found on his/her person or on material he/she legitimately brought into examination hall, e.g. rulers, four figure tables, etc.\n\n   (4). conduct himself/herself in an orderly manner and obey all the instructions of the Invigilator/Examiner.\n\n   (5).  not be engaged in, or attempt any other manner of examination malpractice.\n\nii. Candidates are not expected in the examination hall earlier than 30minutes before the commencement of each examination. They are also advised to keep strictly to the seating arrangements to avoid confusion. Candidates should not, under any circumstances, remove chairs arranged in halls used for examination purposes.\n\niii. Candidates must report at the examination venues punctually at the time scheduled for their papers. Candidates arriving later than half an hour for an examination may be refused enry into the examination hall.\n\niv. Candidates must bring with them to the examination hall their own ink, pen, ruler, erasers and pencils and any materials, which may be permitted by these regulations (as stated hereunder). They are however, not allowed to bring any books or papers, except those that may be permitted or provided by the Department responsible for the examination being held. Candidates are warned in their own interest to ensure that lecture notes, textbooks, jotters, bags, or any other unauthorized materials or aids etc. are not brought into the examination hall.\n\nv. The Invigilator shall search candidates before they are allowed into the examination hall.\n\nvi. To ensure orderliness in the examination hall, seats will be arranged according to the Matric Number or groups taking examinations at each particular time.\n\nvii. Candidates are NOT ALLOWED to be in</string>
    <string name="lasttable">Any other misconduct converting, connected with or pertaining to an\nexamination (it being one of those\nlisted above), which is inimical to or subversive of the integrity of the university examination process, shall be an offence and shall attract appropriate sanctions.</string>
    <string name="offences">1.  LIST OF OFFENCES\nThe following are regarded as acts of examination misconduct, (i) to (xix) are listed as few examples among others:</string>
    <string name="sanction">2.  SANCTIONS \nAny contraventions of any other rules and regulations not listed above shall attract punishment ranging from formal warning to expulsion.</string>
    <!-- student representative council -->
    <string name="introduction_council">In line with the Baptist tradition of democratic ethos and social responsibility and the need to entrench and promote democratic culture, tolerance and team spirit among students, the University August 2014 approved the Student Representative Council (S.R.C). It affords the University the opportunity to identify and address the needs of students and explore means of improving their welfare on campus.\n\nThe Student Representative Council (S.R.C) is a three -tier student governing body namely; the Bowen Baptist Student Fellowship (B.B.S.F), Departmental Presidents, and Hall Management System (H.M.S).\n\nThe Hall Management System (H.M.S) operates in each hall of residence but is directly responsible to the Vice Chancellor and Dean of Students, while the Departmental body report to Heads of Department and Student Affairs Unit.\n\nThe B.B.S.F President functions as the ceremonial head of the S.R.C. However, the Council will elect it own Speaker through the Electoral College system from the representatives and nominees in the Council.</string>
    <string name="aimsandobj">The aims and objectives are for setting up S.R.C and H.M.S are:\n\ni. To promote social, cultural and intellectual activities of students.\n\nii. To foster the general interest of students.\n\niii. To enhance widening leadership prospect of students by making them responsible and allowing them to contribute meaningfully to the development of their community.\n\niv. To serve as a pro-active measure in crisis prevention by using the H.M.S and S.R.C structures for constant Student-Management dialogue.\n\nv. To serve as a training ground on leadership for students.</string>
    <string name="election">(i)  Election into Student Representative Council;\nElections and screening of interested candidates for positions in H.M.S will be conducted by an Electoral Committee set up by Student Affairs Unit with the approval of the Vice Chancellor while S.R.C will draw membership from elected Departmental Presidents, Elected Hall Chairs, and five (5) B.B.S.F nominees. The speaker will be appointed within the council through consensus or Electoral College system of voting. There shall be 2 observers in the council (One Teaching Staff. One Non-Teaching Staff).\n\n(ii)  Election into Hall Management System\nThe Hall Secretary would be the Devotional Leader (1) one, while the Welfare Officer would be the Devotional Leader (2) two, both are representatives of the BBSF in the Hall Executive Committee. All other positions in the Hall Management System are elective.</string>
    <string name="elective">The following are the Requirements for students interested in any elective position of the Hall Management System Executive:\n\ni. Must be a duly registered Bowen student for the academic session and semester.\n\nii. No candidate should have pending cases before S.D.C or any other units in the University, and no candidate should have been sanctioned by S.D.C.\n\niii. No candidate should be on the wanted list of the Law enforcement agencies of the Federal Republic of Nigeria (States, Local Governments) or any Public or Private Organization and other Countries of the world.\n\niv. All candidates interested in elective positions must have a C.G.P.A not less than 2.4 and this will not apply to first year students.\n\nv. All candidates should have proven integrity across the University.</string>
    <!-- student discipliine -->
    <string name="introduction_discipline">The Bowen University enabling law provides that Senate has the power of student discipline. This power can also be exercised by the Vice Chancellor on behalf of Senate. There is a Student Disciplinary Committee, which advises the Vice Chancellor on student discipline. The functions of this committee are investigated and advisory.\nThe University regulations are generally made for orderliness and comfort of the entire university community, including students. However, students are disciplined when they flout these regulations and such is called \“ACT OF MISCONDUCT\”.\nAct of Misconduct can be in broad categories, namely examination malpractice and antisocial behavior.</string>
    <string name="cases">The list of probable offences and stipulated punishments on examination malpractice is given in Chapter 16 of this book.</string>
    <string name="anti_social">The University is meant for men and women whose behaviour is considerate, decent and who respect the rights of others. Any acts which tend to negate these are regarded as antisocial and are punishable.\nExamples of such offences and maximum punishment are tabulated below:</string>
    <string name="sanction_discipline">Other offences not listed above shall attract punishment ranging from formal warning to expulsion.</string>
    <string name="reformatory">Without prejudice to the sanction that may be imposed on any student, he/she maybe required to attend a mandatory reformatory programme before being re-admitted into the University.</string>
    <string name="disobedience">Students who disobey the rules and regulations that govern worship services/devotion such as:\n\ni. coming late to BBSF/Chapel Programme.\n\nii. noise making or conversing during worship service/devotion.\n\niii. absence from Sunday School/devotion.\n\niv. no-display of ID card during worship service.\n\nv. refusal to observe prescribes dress code during worship.\n\nvi. any other act that disturbs or discourages worship service shall attract warning for the first-time offender and attract punishment ranging from rustication for one week to expulsion for a second-time offender.</string>
    <!-- use of social media -->
    <string name="introduction_socialmedia">The global village reality is perhaps more evident today witSh the availability of numerous social media platforms which allow for ease of access and exchange of information to a far-reaching degree. Bowen University recognizes the limitless opportunities that these platforms offer to students for academic and general social interaction. Like every other social benefit, these innovations carry with them tendencies calculated to tarnish the image of the University or its surroundings. It is for this reason that this section is introduced to appraise students of the limit of the use of social media while within the outside the premises of the University.</string>
    <string name="definition_social">Social media refer to the means of interaction (through computer-mediated technologies such as mobile phones, laptops, iPad, smartphones, etc.) among interactants where they create, share, and other forms of expression in virtual communities and networks through platforms created for these to happen.</string>
    <string name="types">The scope of Social Media is increasing by the day. This is as a result of the Information Age where opportunities abound for creative development of platforms which meet general and or specified needs of individuals and communities. Bowen University recognizes this is a way to increase the scope of learning and ingenuity of students, but the institution frown at any attempt to use these platforms for calculated and or unintentional tarnishing of the image of the University. As such, the University appreciates the benefits of the following types of social media platforms will keep increasing in form and use as time goes on.</string>
    <string name="useofsocialmedia">The following are the uses of social media that are not acceptable to bowen University:\n\n1.  Pornography \nViewing, posting and sharing of nude, obscene pictures or video either hard core or soft core of students and non-students are not allowed.\n\n2.  Abusive/derogatory contents\nStudents are no allowed to use the social media to send abusive or offensive contents about students or any member of staff between or among themselves.\n\n3.  Photographs/Video Recording\nStudents are not allowed to capture the photographs or video of students and staff either within any part of the University or outside without the express permission of the individual.\n\n4.  Students are not allowed to use social media to blackmail, perpetrate fraud, incite other students against the University authority and or use it in such a way as to put the name of the University in disrepute.</string>

    <!-- About_fragment -->
    <string name="description_about">Bowen Student Handbook is the official resource that defines our expectation for student life. These are the policies and practises that allow us to collaboratively work alongside each other, to respectively respond to conflicts with one another, and resolve violations of our Code of Conduct in ways that emphasize learning and personal accountability.</string>

</resources>
